

Contact



B-601, Rajyash Riverium, South Vasna, tAhmedabad



nikhilmakwana1987 @gmail.com



+91-8866-719-322

Skills

Blogging, Content Creation, SEO, SEM, SMM, Email Campaigns, CRM, UX/UI, Digital Strategies, **Data Analysis**

Tools

Master of Excel, Google Analytics, Google Search Console, Google Ads, Google Tag Manager, MailChimp, Aweber, **Facebook Business**

Tools

HootSuit, Buffer, Bitly, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe AI, Adobe Lightroom, WordPress, Hosting cPanel

Education

Bachelor in Computer Application (2008)

C.O. Jani Institute of Technology Bhavnagar University

Work Links



www.igeeksblog.com



iGeeksBlog



(O) /iGB_Hindi



/iGeeksBlog



/iGeeksBlog



🞳 /iGeeksBlog Hindi

Nikhil Makwana Creative Head & Digital Marketing Lead

Summary

Seasoned digital marketer with 11+ years of experience building and implementing strategies focused on content-driven SEO, Social Media, content planner, content producer, branding & re-branding, reputation management, email marketing, paid campaigns, print media, public speaker, and team training & management. Had led small to medium teams to achieve goals for traffic increase, brand awareness, and create opportunities to generate revenues in different ways.

Work Experience

Creative Head @ iGeeks Media Private Limited Oct 2019 - Present

- Implemented Social Media Strategies that boosted social media account (Instagram) from 3400 followers to 150K followers in 24 Months organically. Planned and curated quality content as a content producer for You-
- Tube and various social media channels that gained 460% Growth in 30 Months.
- Executed Re-branding of iGeeksBlog, which included Logo Design and Trademark Registration. Developed a website with an understanding of different web host-
- ing environments that meets Search Engines Requirements (web vitals, user experience, quick load, and more). Have been a key member in planning a content-driven SEO strate-
- gy that boosted site visits by 180% in 12 months while increasing total revenue by approx 40%.
- Started new products/channels iGB_Hindi, iGeeks Magazine, 3 New Podcasts channels, designed and introduced merchandise, weekly newsletters, and a few more.

Digital Marketing Manager @ Techno Pixels

June 2016 - Present

- Got the opportunity to work on differnt content platforms like media
- Worked as content planner, editor, and publisher.
- Responsible to plan and execute SEO and Social Media Strategies that lead to the growth of the platform.
- Focused on Social Media Strategies, Paid Campaigns in Google & Facebook Ads, Email campaigns, organic link building, and other online activities.

Digital Marketing Manager @ Intesols Pty LTD

Nov 2014 to March 2016

- Developed Organic Local SEO Strategies for 80+ clients during 14
- Months. Have been part of company growth from 37 clients to 83 clients just in
- 14 Months. Responsible for hiring the right candidate and building a team from 8 members to 19 members.
- Managed team of SEOs, Social Media Executives, Content & Copy Writers, Graphic Designers, Developers, and account managers.

Product Marketer @ Azilen Technologies Private Limited Oct 2013 to Sep 2014

- Responsible for online and offline marketing campaigns of the compa
- ny's software products. Planned and implemented 360-degree marketing campaigns to promote products.
- Designed SEO and Social Media Strategies that increased product visibility by 55% in 10 Months.
- Implemented online and offline media marketing that supported App installation in users' devices.

Sr. SEO Executive @ Cygnet Infotech Private Limited April 2008 to Aug 2013

- Joined as a Jr. SEO Executive and managed 3 SEO projects for 11 Months.
- Have been a key point of contact for many clients.
- Trained people for SEO and Social Media things and managed a team of 3 members and 12 projects.
- Managed online product marketing for two software products of a company.

Strengths

Growth Mindset

Always striving to be the best version of myself. I think this goes hand in hand with marketing, which is here to help companies grow.

know what I aim for.

set short and long-term goals.

Result Oriented I always make sure to create roadmaps before any new project to

Time Management I believe in it to prioritize my assignments, Manage my calendar, and